<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Motivation on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/tags/motivation/</link><description>Recent content in Motivation on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy New Year!!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/cover5.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Happy New Year!!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="happy-new-year"&gt;HAPPY NEW YEAR!!!!!!!!!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi all!! I hope everyone reading this had a decent christmas and new year celebration (and if you chilled out like I did, I hope it was pleasant!) If you are a close friend or family member, you probably know I have been doing the Project 365 challenge on Instagram for the last 36 days! I did start early, but for some reason I felt like if I didn&amp;rsquo;t start during December, I would completely forget to do it for the new year (like my younger brother did! &lt;em&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m calling you out&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two challenges I want to stick to this year that are my top priority, and a couple others that aren&amp;rsquo;t as important. I&amp;rsquo;ve also started my sixth quarter in college, and all ten weeks are going to be jam-packed with five classes Monday through Thursday 8:30am till 5pm, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be waking up at 6am every morning&amp;hellip; 🫠 Thankfully, on Friday&amp;rsquo;s I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go to class until 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="new-quarter-new-me-bottom-priorities"&gt;New Quarter, New Me (Bottom Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My less-important priorities are for minor betterment. I want to wear makeup and fun-style earrings more often! And I have been, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel bad about it or think I look bad for forgetting or being too lazy. I am also going to try to hold myself somewhat accountable for learning outside of school; This includes learning Spanish, getting better at understanding and writing code, and learning about data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been (as I mentioned) posting to Instagram everyday for the Project 365 challenge. This isn&amp;rsquo;t typically important, but it is helping me be more present in my life and the lives of people that want to know me. For the last couple days, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to quickly take a random snapshot of something unimportant to my day, simply because I keep doomscrolling on TikTok and Instagram reels. I took a look at my watch-time on Tiktok, and my average for December is around 3.5 hours (at least one full week could be put together of days spent 5 hours on Tiktok alone), and I can feel my brain slowly rotting. I want to do better, I want better for myself, and I want to be present in my own life. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend my days sitting on my couch drowning in my phone. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the end result will be my going out with friends, on dates with my husband, and spending time outdoors with camping, hiking, or even just sitting in a park while I read or crochet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="resolutions-or-whatever-top-priorities"&gt;Resolutions, Or Whatever (Top Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sooo there&amp;rsquo;s a reading challenge I found via &amp;lsquo;jananie&amp;rsquo; called The Anti-Brain-Rot Challenge!! It&amp;rsquo;s based around building consistency, forming your own opinions, and consuming media mindfully. Here are all the rules of this challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="building-consistency"&gt;Building Consistency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read for at least one 45 minute session per day, where you (optionally) annotate what you read. This includes physical books, e-books, and audio books. This helps you hit that mindful consumption goal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; article or essay per month on any topic that interests you. These can be academic essays, news articles, or even a blog like this one! For advanced challengers, you can read one article or essay &lt;em&gt;per week&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book by a BIPOC author for every book you read by a white author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mindfully-consume-media"&gt;Mindfully Consume Media
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; genre&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Literary fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Historical fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science Fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Romance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; History or Political&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Memoir or Biography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A play&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A graphic novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; An anthology or short story collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A translated book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from each of the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a queer main character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a disability representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an author NOT from North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a black author who is &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an indigenous author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a SWANA (Southwest Asian and North African) author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a latin author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an east Asian author that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Chinese, Japanese, or Korean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a south Asian author who is not Indian&lt;br&gt;
Thankfully, each requirement doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to match &lt;em&gt;each individual book&lt;/em&gt;, we can have multiple requirements in &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; book! That will make this challenge much less daunting!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="thinking-critically--forming-your-own-opinions"&gt;Thinking Critically / Forming Your Own Opinions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Create your own critical media journal: write down notes or reviews on each book you read, each movie or show you watch, and each article or essay you read. I will be doing this here, and (if I have a lot to say) I may make a whole blog post about my reviews!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big thing I want to prioritize this year is excersize. I want to not only grow a phat ass (lol) but I want functional strength. I want my hips to support me better and not hurt from simply walking, and I especially want stronger shoulders that don&amp;rsquo;t crack and pop with every movement, and I want to be able to lift almost anything above my shoulders (which, the heaviest things I can lift &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; are my 10lb cats).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found this guy David (movementwithdavid on IG) whose favorite excersize is &lt;em&gt;functional movement and stretches&lt;/em&gt;! I have a few videos of his that are based around the hips, arms, and shoulders and how to keep them mobile and strong. I definitely plan on referencing his content as needed for my workouts! My main goal for working out is to avoid any severe decline in my mobility. I want to be the old lady who struts around the park with flare, instead of the old lady who has been relying on a walker since the moment she turned 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to find attainable goals for yourself! Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a small or large change, any positive change is &lt;em&gt;GOOD&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I gotta pay attention in class. TTFN!! 😃&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Life, Media, and What Matters</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/cover3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Life, Media, and What Matters" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="my-last-3-days-so-far"&gt;My Last 3 Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, all! &lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s a new day, and this is my first post post-thanksgiving (hehe)! I slept pretty badly last night (as per the last few nights) but I got to take a 2 hour nap, and was then invited on a bike ride with my husband and our roommate D! This was D&amp;rsquo;s first time riding a road bike specifically, and to be honest, he did just fine. He was especially nervous about riding with drop handlebars, but over the weeks I guess he&amp;rsquo;d gotten used to the idea, and he did awesome! It was funny though, I was leading the trail with D behind me and my husband at the back (because he&amp;rsquo;s the fastest and most experienced), and about 3 times D had either fallen into a chain-link fence (which saved him from &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; falling) or he hand nearly fallen but caught himself, and all of this happened because he was going too slow while waiting for me to go ahead of him&amp;hellip; lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anywho! We also stopped at the local skate park/ shop nearby, after finding out on Instagram that a local mutual aid organization is collecting winter clothing and survival items for our homeless community, and dropped off seven fluffy crochet beanies I made earlier this year. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to make more, and I might make a couple warm blankets or mittens and scarves. Last thing we did together today was stop at Trek to buy D a helmet that fits (he&amp;rsquo;s got a pretty thick noggin), and grab food at the mall on our way home. D, by the way, is unofficially our roommate, as he and another friend will be moving in with us in a couple months. So tonight, D stayed back at their place to play games with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="class-research---billionaires-suck"&gt;Class Research - Billionaires Suck
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just got done doing research on how to hold billionaires accountable to slow down the climate crisis, and successfully found &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; reliable papers&amp;hellip; I might have to expand my research juuuust a touch. Thankfully my calculus homework is done minus the very last question, and yes I do in fact still hate math (you can&amp;rsquo;t convince me to like it, I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with anti-derivatives). I am officially mostly caught up on homework! If I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned it yet, I am a 29 year old college student in my second year of college, I have two best friends who are 10 years younger (yes, it&amp;rsquo;s weird, and yes, I have communicated that unequal power dynamics make me super uncomfy, they have agreed to let me know if things change in a bad way) and my degree is software engineering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="a-late-intro"&gt;A Late Intro
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am also a part of the LGBTQ community, I go by they/them pronouns, and I feel a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; strong sense of justice! If human rights, animals, the LGBTQ, respecting insects, and our climate crisis don&amp;rsquo;t align with your beliefs, then we will not appreciate each other and you are not welcome to continue reading (although I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news---palestine"&gt;World News - Palestine
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of world-news, have you heard the new movie / documentary coming out? It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The Voice of Hind Rajab&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched it past the trailor, and I still cried. I remember vividly when the news of her murder came out, what those people had put her through. Wesam Rajab, Hind&amp;rsquo;s mother, has become an advocate for the children of Gaza who all have died, or are dying and fearing for their lives. All children deserve to be free of the fate that was forced onto Hind. And NO, there is no such thing as Palistinians being trained soldiers from &lt;em&gt;literal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;birth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. That is what the people YOU hate want you to believe, and you&amp;rsquo;re straight falling for it. Anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="us-news---mmiw"&gt;US News - MMIW
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, in American news, &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-admin-removes-report-on-missing-native-americans-11063830" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;the Trump admin removed an important report on MMIW&lt;/a&gt;. MMIW means &amp;ldquo;Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women [and children]. The report is called Not One More, and the senator who was part of the commitee to introduce the 2020 Not Invisible Act had noticed it disappeared from the DOJ&amp;rsquo;s website. This is huge, because not only is MMIW a very ignored American crisis, but it just shows that this Admin &lt;em&gt;does not care about the MMIW crisis&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, a DOJ spokesperson was quoted saying the report was removed to &amp;ldquo;ensure compliance&amp;rdquo; to an executive order, which then states &amp;ldquo;women are biologically female, and men are biologically male.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;What that has to do with MMIW, I have no fucking idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, not only are Native Americans and Native Alaskans still being politically abused and ignored, but they&amp;rsquo;re quickly being erased in a violent way. This will allow &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; Indigenous women and children to go missing and/or turn up murdered, and no one will be forced to care, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should all be angry about this. Goodnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Photo owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstock.adobe.com%2Fsearch%3Fk%3Dgradient%2Bcover&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDiAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;Adobe Stock Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First Post" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving 2025. It is 1:41pm and 55°F, which is wonderfully chilly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house with my husband and another friend, to spend Thanksgiving dinner with this friend and his family. &lt;br&gt;
I want to take a second to give space to all of the Native American tribes that were abused, murdered, kidnapped, and ultimately changed by settlers who took everything from Native people. You all deserve peace, to have your land back, and to have your languages back and your pre-colonial history not forgotten or erased. &lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t really celebrate Thanksgiving, because of its history. My only &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; is the excuse to see friends (like this friend) who I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get to see outside of special occasions and holidays, due to both parties being too busy on a normal basis. &lt;br&gt;
It feels like with adulthood comes the lack of care for holidays. I tried to hold onto it, the childhood magic that your family desperately holds onto for you and your cousins. However, growing up came with living across the country from the rest of your family, which then comes with never seeing your relatives (and never messaging or trying to see each other because neither of you seem to care at all), and over the years you end up feeling estranged from everyone. Thankfully I still keep up with one cousin and my younger brother, and they both keep up with me (and I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; thankful for them!) &lt;br&gt;
Anyways, this blog is going to be my way of processing life. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go to therapy yet, as my school schedule is so busy, but I know I still need to be responsible to myself and take care of my mental health. So, I will be talking about college and things I learn and struggle with, exciting things that happen (like how I was elected to the Unified Student Government), vacations, things with friends, drama, and personal things like how I saw a nutritionist and was told I was in &amp;ldquo;mild starvation&amp;rdquo; and how horrified I was. If you took the time to read all of this, thank you, and I hope you stick around for my other posts &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>