<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>This Week and Its Many Issues</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/cover5.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This Week and Its Many Issues" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="day-so-far"&gt;Day So Far
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello and holy shit it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; Thursday&amp;hellip; It has been a WEEK and the damn things not even over yet. I&amp;rsquo;ve had to stay up past midnight 3 nights in a row when my bedtime is 10pm, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been running on 6ish hours of sleep for three days. I am finally all caught up on each assignment (thank goodness I wasn&amp;rsquo;t that far behind)! However, crunch time hasn&amp;rsquo;t ended and won&amp;rsquo;t end until around December 11th or 12th. I have a breakfast meeting with the president of my school for the USG meeting at freaking 9AM tomorrow morning, which means I don&amp;rsquo;t get to sleep in like usual. Then I have calculus in the afternoon for an hour. THEN I get to relax and study until a USG team bonding event at 6pm which could go on past 9pm. Then I have my math exam at 1pm Saturday. 🫠 My anxiety meds are the only reason why I haven&amp;rsquo;t given up at this current point of exhaustion. It&amp;rsquo;s 7:22pm right now, and I definitely think I&amp;rsquo;m going to shower soon and get to bed by 10pm again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="calculus"&gt;Calculus
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sooo&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m failing calculus!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m already weak with math in general, but calculus is a whole new demon. Even my three smartest classmates keep getting confused and stuck on these problems. I haven&amp;rsquo;t given up, but I do only have one week left, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to shift my focus to my other classes, as well as setting myself up with an online calculus course that will be overall cheaper than a weekly tutoring session. Now that I at least have some calculus under my belt, I know I&amp;rsquo;m at least going to have better luck this time around. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this online course because my student advocate suggested it, and she said if I complete the course with a passing grade, I can easily transfer the credits and I won&amp;rsquo;t have to retake the class at all! I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly grateful for her, she understands and told me that this is one of the three most failed courses (english comp and educational learning theories being the other two.. because students are lazy as hell). I was pretty broken up about failing this class, but it&amp;rsquo;s comforting to know that it won&amp;rsquo;t effect the rest of my degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="english-comp"&gt;English Comp
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a research paper about billionaires and their effect on the environment, as well as how technology can help slow climate change AND hold billionaires accountable. Did you know, there is a technology called Blockchain that hosts software that can track corporations and companies carbon emissions, and they get &amp;ldquo;carbon credits&amp;rdquo; when they hit their carbon emisson reduction goals?? That&amp;rsquo;s freaking awesome! There was also a satellite called the MethaneSAT, which would view the Earth and track the source of carbon emissions, and track &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; was emitting the most carbon and methane!! Technology is freaking amazing, and I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful for the opportunity to become a software engineer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho&amp;hellip;.. It&amp;rsquo;s 11:15pm and past my bedtime :D yippeeeee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Image Owned By &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fkr.pinterest.com%2Fpin%2F122160208638550196%2F&amp;psig=AOvVaw2Kn71TAIM6oTf6w1ffYF7j&amp;ust=1764919783593000&amp;source=images&amp;cd=vfe&amp;opi=89978449&amp;ved=0CBUQjhxqFwoTCJDo7t20o5EDFQAAAAAdAAAAABAE"&gt;The Gypsy Goddess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/cover4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="days-so-far"&gt;Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="sunday-nov-30"&gt;Sunday, Nov 30
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello again! Yesterday was a particularly relaxing day; We all woke up to snow and sleet, and 33°F, barely breezy! Definitely too cold for a bike ride. Productivity was low, but laundry got half done (still gotta fold it&amp;hellip;), dishes got done (thank you, hubby!) and the blog was edited. I started learning how to knit after I&amp;rsquo;ve been crocheting for the last five years, and I honestly love it so far! I got myself used to casting the yarn onto the needles, creating a &amp;ldquo;magic join&amp;rdquo; so I can work in the round, and I am now making my first hat! It is taking some time, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it will still be faster than using crochet. With this new skill, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping making things like hats, socks, and sweaters will be easier and faster than crocheting them (also, crochet socks &lt;em&gt;SUUUCK&lt;/em&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="monday-dec-1"&gt;Monday, Dec 1
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="shout-out-to-big-sis"&gt;Shout Out to Big Sis!!
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I feel like a jackass, I forgot my older sisters friggin BIRTHDAY yesterday!!! 😭 I am &lt;strong&gt;SO&lt;/strong&gt; sorry, big sis!!! I think she turned 40 this year&amp;hellip; I turn 30 next year, gosh I feel old as hell. I also want to shout out this same sister, because I was thinking about our childhood a couple days ago. We didn&amp;rsquo;t always get along, but she never failed to support me and make me feel loved. I never felt alone with her. I remember when she would do my makeup and curl my hair for my school chorus concerts and school dances. She never made me feel like I was a burden, or like she hated me for it. Sis, I hope you see this, and I want you to know that I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for you. You made me feel beautiful when my bullies made me feel ugly, and you took care of me even though you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had to. You were also just a kid back then. I love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="today-at-school"&gt;Today At School
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m back at school after a 4 day weekend from thanksgiving, and today I have Developing Scalable Weeb Applications, where we learn how to connect our code projects to a database and use SQL in our code to help us build and modify the data in our database. I also have Calculus, Intro to English Comp, and Web-Based Software Projects, which ends at 8pm each night. Most of these classes I like, especially the last class. It&amp;rsquo;s a project class where we work on teams of three to create a web-based application using a database. My team is currently working to create a webapp similar to the OG twitter, but for shower thoughts! No pictures, no videos, no threads&amp;hellip; Only posts, reactions, and maybe replies! I am very excited for the end product, and I will make sure to post screenshots when it&amp;rsquo;s done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also a member of my schools Unified Student Government (yippee!!!) as a Senator. Today we discussed student initiatives, and thanks to my suggestion we are soon getting a brand new refridgerator dedicated for the students! WOO! Finally we won&amp;rsquo;t have to compete with the school clubs and activites for fridge space. We also discussed ways to encourage third-year students to actually show up to their internships (because TWO companies backed out of working with our school due to so many students not showing up). So far our ideas are to create large posters to put at least a couple on each floor (it&amp;rsquo;s a very small school), and have a QR code for students to see &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the internships are about about, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they work, and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they are so important (our careers quite literally rely on it). But we&amp;rsquo;ll see how well that goes over, or whether these lazy bunch of students will ruin a good thing &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; for the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news"&gt;World News
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="ad-fatigue"&gt;Ad Fatigue
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video on Tiktok about ad fatigue, oh my GOODNESS I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; damn tired of ALL the ads!!! &lt;strong&gt;Everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;!!! Instagram and Pinterest are especially egregious, Pinterest you can&amp;rsquo;t even tell what&amp;rsquo;s an ad and what&amp;rsquo;s a post, and every time you try to scroll you end up triggering a random ad to go to its link. On Instagram, almost every other post is some sort of ad, and &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; every 2 reels videos is one or two ads. Luckily, tiktok ads are (for now) relatively easy to get rid of, and my husband and I pay for Youtube Premium so no ads there (and he found an extension that blocks promotions inside each video on our TVs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, why the hell am I getting marketing emails for companies I&amp;rsquo;ve either never heard of or don&amp;rsquo;t have an account with?? It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that hitting &amp;ldquo;unubscribe&amp;rdquo; from the majority of these emails doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Oh yeah, this also happens because your email gets sold. So that&amp;rsquo;s freaking &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Black Friday also isn&amp;rsquo;t the same thing it was when I was a child, not even a full 20 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole month long debacle where sales only go up to a regular 40% when it used to go up to 80% or 90%. Companies (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Target, Michaels, and Amazon) are even faking sales, where they hike up the price and make the sale price match the &lt;em&gt;original damn price!!!&lt;/em&gt; People are already boycotting these companies (as they damn well should) and soon it&amp;rsquo;s going to bite the rich in the ass (Target and Starbucks are already feeling the pain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The lines between being a human being and being a brand are so blurred that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to distinguish between the two.&amp;rdquo; Hannah Glenn&amp;rsquo;s (@hannahglennhannahglenn on tiktok) recent video is why I decided to write on this topic. She talks about how nothing in life feels like an authentic experience anymore, and I wholeheartedly agree. From making friends and going out to hang, to watching your favorite creator on your platform of choice. Every time someone creates a good new thing, they end up getting a hard on for the concept of capitalism and making even a tiiiiiny bit more money through ad revenue. You can&amp;rsquo;t even go on a nice walk anymore without seeing at a minimum of one influencer &lt;em&gt;per walk outside&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d be surprised if smaller countries didn&amp;rsquo;t start banning the act of influencing because of the sheer amount of assholery that these weirdos perform just to get a few extra clicks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen way too many videos of influencers getting dragged online for abusing waitstaff or killing homeless people in the name of a &amp;ldquo;joke&amp;rdquo; (fuck you, Nat Reynolds, you don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to forget even though you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;only human&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho. I gotta get started on my project class&amp;rsquo; work. TTFN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you know me personally and read this far, let me know if there&amp;rsquo;s anything you want me to talk about from my perspective! ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Image Owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.freepik.com%2Ffree-photos-vectors%2Fabstract-gradient-background&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDHAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;FreePik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Life, Media, and What Matters</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/cover3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Life, Media, and What Matters" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="my-last-3-days-so-far"&gt;My Last 3 Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, all! &lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s a new day, and this is my first post post-thanksgiving (hehe)! I slept pretty badly last night (as per the last few nights) but I got to take a 2 hour nap, and was then invited on a bike ride with my husband and our roommate D! This was D&amp;rsquo;s first time riding a road bike specifically, and to be honest, he did just fine. He was especially nervous about riding with drop handlebars, but over the weeks I guess he&amp;rsquo;d gotten used to the idea, and he did awesome! It was funny though, I was leading the trail with D behind me and my husband at the back (because he&amp;rsquo;s the fastest and most experienced), and about 3 times D had either fallen into a chain-link fence (which saved him from &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; falling) or he hand nearly fallen but caught himself, and all of this happened because he was going too slow while waiting for me to go ahead of him&amp;hellip; lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anywho! We also stopped at the local skate park/ shop nearby, after finding out on Instagram that a local mutual aid organization is collecting winter clothing and survival items for our homeless community, and dropped off seven fluffy crochet beanies I made earlier this year. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to make more, and I might make a couple warm blankets or mittens and scarves. Last thing we did together today was stop at Trek to buy D a helmet that fits (he&amp;rsquo;s got a pretty thick noggin), and grab food at the mall on our way home. D, by the way, is unofficially our roommate, as he and another friend will be moving in with us in a couple months. So tonight, D stayed back at their place to play games with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="class-research---billionaires-suck"&gt;Class Research - Billionaires Suck
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just got done doing research on how to hold billionaires accountable to slow down the climate crisis, and successfully found &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; reliable papers&amp;hellip; I might have to expand my research juuuust a touch. Thankfully my calculus homework is done minus the very last question, and yes I do in fact still hate math (you can&amp;rsquo;t convince me to like it, I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with anti-derivatives). I am officially mostly caught up on homework! If I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned it yet, I am a 29 year old college student in my second year of college, I have two best friends who are 10 years younger (yes, it&amp;rsquo;s weird, and yes, I have communicated that unequal power dynamics make me super uncomfy, they have agreed to let me know if things change in a bad way) and my degree is software engineering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="a-late-intro"&gt;A Late Intro
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am also a part of the LGBTQ community, I go by they/them pronouns, and I feel a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; strong sense of justice! If human rights, animals, the LGBTQ, respecting insects, and our climate crisis don&amp;rsquo;t align with your beliefs, then we will not appreciate each other and you are not welcome to continue reading (although I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news---palestine"&gt;World News - Palestine
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of world-news, have you heard the new movie / documentary coming out? It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The Voice of Hind Rajab&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched it past the trailor, and I still cried. I remember vividly when the news of her murder came out, what those people had put her through. Wesam Rajab, Hind&amp;rsquo;s mother, has become an advocate for the children of Gaza who all have died, or are dying and fearing for their lives. All children deserve to be free of the fate that was forced onto Hind. And NO, there is no such thing as Palistinians being trained soldiers from &lt;em&gt;literal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;birth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. That is what the people YOU hate want you to believe, and you&amp;rsquo;re straight falling for it. Anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="us-news---mmiw"&gt;US News - MMIW
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, in American news, &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-admin-removes-report-on-missing-native-americans-11063830" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;the Trump admin removed an important report on MMIW&lt;/a&gt;. MMIW means &amp;ldquo;Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women [and children]. The report is called Not One More, and the senator who was part of the commitee to introduce the 2020 Not Invisible Act had noticed it disappeared from the DOJ&amp;rsquo;s website. This is huge, because not only is MMIW a very ignored American crisis, but it just shows that this Admin &lt;em&gt;does not care about the MMIW crisis&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, a DOJ spokesperson was quoted saying the report was removed to &amp;ldquo;ensure compliance&amp;rdquo; to an executive order, which then states &amp;ldquo;women are biologically female, and men are biologically male.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;What that has to do with MMIW, I have no fucking idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, not only are Native Americans and Native Alaskans still being politically abused and ignored, but they&amp;rsquo;re quickly being erased in a violent way. This will allow &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; Indigenous women and children to go missing and/or turn up murdered, and no one will be forced to care, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should all be angry about this. Goodnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Photo owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstock.adobe.com%2Fsearch%3Fk%3Dgradient%2Bcover&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDiAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;Adobe Stock Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First Post" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving 2025. It is 1:41pm and 55°F, which is wonderfully chilly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house with my husband and another friend, to spend Thanksgiving dinner with this friend and his family. &lt;br&gt;
I want to take a second to give space to all of the Native American tribes that were abused, murdered, kidnapped, and ultimately changed by settlers who took everything from Native people. You all deserve peace, to have your land back, and to have your languages back and your pre-colonial history not forgotten or erased. &lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t really celebrate Thanksgiving, because of its history. My only &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; is the excuse to see friends (like this friend) who I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get to see outside of special occasions and holidays, due to both parties being too busy on a normal basis. &lt;br&gt;
It feels like with adulthood comes the lack of care for holidays. I tried to hold onto it, the childhood magic that your family desperately holds onto for you and your cousins. However, growing up came with living across the country from the rest of your family, which then comes with never seeing your relatives (and never messaging or trying to see each other because neither of you seem to care at all), and over the years you end up feeling estranged from everyone. Thankfully I still keep up with one cousin and my younger brother, and they both keep up with me (and I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; thankful for them!) &lt;br&gt;
Anyways, this blog is going to be my way of processing life. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go to therapy yet, as my school schedule is so busy, but I know I still need to be responsible to myself and take care of my mental health. So, I will be talking about college and things I learn and struggle with, exciting things that happen (like how I was elected to the Unified Student Government), vacations, things with friends, drama, and personal things like how I saw a nutritionist and was told I was in &amp;ldquo;mild starvation&amp;rdquo; and how horrified I was. If you took the time to read all of this, thank you, and I hope you stick around for my other posts &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>