<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/categories/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy New Year!!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/cover5.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Happy New Year!!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="happy-new-year"&gt;HAPPY NEW YEAR!!!!!!!!!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi all!! I hope everyone reading this had a decent christmas and new year celebration (and if you chilled out like I did, I hope it was pleasant!) If you are a close friend or family member, you probably know I have been doing the Project 365 challenge on Instagram for the last 36 days! I did start early, but for some reason I felt like if I didn&amp;rsquo;t start during December, I would completely forget to do it for the new year (like my younger brother did! &lt;em&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m calling you out&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two challenges I want to stick to this year that are my top priority, and a couple others that aren&amp;rsquo;t as important. I&amp;rsquo;ve also started my sixth quarter in college, and all ten weeks are going to be jam-packed with five classes Monday through Thursday 8:30am till 5pm, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be waking up at 6am every morning&amp;hellip; 🫠 Thankfully, on Friday&amp;rsquo;s I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go to class until 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="new-quarter-new-me-bottom-priorities"&gt;New Quarter, New Me (Bottom Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My less-important priorities are for minor betterment. I want to wear makeup and fun-style earrings more often! And I have been, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel bad about it or think I look bad for forgetting or being too lazy. I am also going to try to hold myself somewhat accountable for learning outside of school; This includes learning Spanish, getting better at understanding and writing code, and learning about data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been (as I mentioned) posting to Instagram everyday for the Project 365 challenge. This isn&amp;rsquo;t typically important, but it is helping me be more present in my life and the lives of people that want to know me. For the last couple days, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to quickly take a random snapshot of something unimportant to my day, simply because I keep doomscrolling on TikTok and Instagram reels. I took a look at my watch-time on Tiktok, and my average for December is around 3.5 hours (at least one full week could be put together of days spent 5 hours on Tiktok alone), and I can feel my brain slowly rotting. I want to do better, I want better for myself, and I want to be present in my own life. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend my days sitting on my couch drowning in my phone. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the end result will be my going out with friends, on dates with my husband, and spending time outdoors with camping, hiking, or even just sitting in a park while I read or crochet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="resolutions-or-whatever-top-priorities"&gt;Resolutions, Or Whatever (Top Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sooo there&amp;rsquo;s a reading challenge I found via &amp;lsquo;jananie&amp;rsquo; called The Anti-Brain-Rot Challenge!! It&amp;rsquo;s based around building consistency, forming your own opinions, and consuming media mindfully. Here are all the rules of this challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="building-consistency"&gt;Building Consistency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read for at least one 45 minute session per day, where you (optionally) annotate what you read. This includes physical books, e-books, and audio books. This helps you hit that mindful consumption goal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; article or essay per month on any topic that interests you. These can be academic essays, news articles, or even a blog like this one! For advanced challengers, you can read one article or essay &lt;em&gt;per week&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book by a BIPOC author for every book you read by a white author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mindfully-consume-media"&gt;Mindfully Consume Media
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; genre&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Literary fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Historical fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science Fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Romance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; History or Political&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Memoir or Biography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A play&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A graphic novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; An anthology or short story collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A translated book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from each of the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a queer main character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a disability representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an author NOT from North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a black author who is &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an indigenous author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a SWANA (Southwest Asian and North African) author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a latin author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an east Asian author that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Chinese, Japanese, or Korean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a south Asian author who is not Indian&lt;br&gt;
Thankfully, each requirement doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to match &lt;em&gt;each individual book&lt;/em&gt;, we can have multiple requirements in &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; book! That will make this challenge much less daunting!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="thinking-critically--forming-your-own-opinions"&gt;Thinking Critically / Forming Your Own Opinions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Create your own critical media journal: write down notes or reviews on each book you read, each movie or show you watch, and each article or essay you read. I will be doing this here, and (if I have a lot to say) I may make a whole blog post about my reviews!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big thing I want to prioritize this year is excersize. I want to not only grow a phat ass (lol) but I want functional strength. I want my hips to support me better and not hurt from simply walking, and I especially want stronger shoulders that don&amp;rsquo;t crack and pop with every movement, and I want to be able to lift almost anything above my shoulders (which, the heaviest things I can lift &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; are my 10lb cats).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found this guy David (movementwithdavid on IG) whose favorite excersize is &lt;em&gt;functional movement and stretches&lt;/em&gt;! I have a few videos of his that are based around the hips, arms, and shoulders and how to keep them mobile and strong. I definitely plan on referencing his content as needed for my workouts! My main goal for working out is to avoid any severe decline in my mobility. I want to be the old lady who struts around the park with flare, instead of the old lady who has been relying on a walker since the moment she turned 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to find attainable goals for yourself! Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a small or large change, any positive change is &lt;em&gt;GOOD&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I gotta pay attention in class. TTFN!! 😃&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Christmas Vacation So Far!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/cover3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Christmas Vacation So Far!" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-vacation-so-far"&gt;My Vacation So Far
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hellooooo!!! It&amp;rsquo;s been a hot minute since my last post, I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely been allowing myself the time to be lazy (and allowing things to pile up so I have more interesting things to talk about). To be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s been nice! I&amp;rsquo;m allowed to relax and not take too much seriously. The last couple days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been vegging out on the couch with one of my roommates binging &lt;em&gt;True Blood&lt;/em&gt; while she plays &lt;em&gt;Skyrim&lt;/em&gt; and I knit. Except knitting isn&amp;rsquo;t going too well, because the damn hat I&amp;rsquo;m working on isn&amp;rsquo;t getting smaller while I decrease the stitches, which is getting annoying&amp;hellip; But I guess I should count the stitches I have now and actually make sure there are less than I started with. Anywho!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="packing-and-moving"&gt;Packing and Moving
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned previously that my husband and I will be moving into a house with two of my school friends, and we found a store with cardboard boxes! They sell small boxes for $1, medium for $1.50, and large boxes (which are huge) for $1.75, so it was a friggin steal! Right now the boxes I got are sitting in the truck bed until I grab our hand-truck to bring them inside, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get all the small crap I&amp;rsquo;ve collected over the last couple years organized and into boxes! Also, while I&amp;rsquo;ve started slowly packing, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to figure out where all of my crystals went to and wrap them up all nice in the bubble wrap! The last thing I want is to break even more crystals 😅 One roommate already broke my mini-penis fluorite crystal (it was in a bad spot, and he yeeted it onto the floor with a cable). Now he owes me a new mini-penis! 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="paganism---my-altar"&gt;Paganism - My Altar
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of packing and finding things.. Since roommate A has moved into our apartment (while we wait to find a house), she is also a practicing pagan, we&amp;rsquo;ve bonded over that and have both set up separate altars on my media center! Here&amp;rsquo;s mine:
&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar.jpg"
width="3024"
height="3024"
srcset="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar_hu_e2c7a33124342d67.jpg 480w, https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar_hu_c9246ee81edddee7.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="My Alter To The Morrigan, Freyja, and Aphrodite"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;
Here I have my altar (keeping A&amp;rsquo;s altar private), where I have dedicated space to The Morrigan, Freyja, and Aphrodite. I spent time with my Crow Tarot deck to see if The Morrigan and Freyja want to work with me, and their responses were quite apt. The Morrigan said I need to quit being lazy and get a hold on my anger (which has come up once again because I&amp;rsquo;m not used to dealing with not-so-mature brains who can&amp;rsquo;t handle my overly sarcastic remarks&amp;hellip;which can be mean to people who don&amp;rsquo;t know me well enough, or people who are especially sensitive in a specfic moment), but she is still willing to work with me as long as I am active in my devotion. Freyja I have already worked with in my past, before I became too lazy and forgotten our relationship. Her tarot reading told me I need more patience in my everyday life, which I agree with, and trying to keep a pin on to hold myself accountable. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet done a reading for Aphrodite, which I feel sorry for. I&amp;rsquo;m about to work out with roommate A and then shower, so I can be clean for Aphrodite&amp;rsquo;s reading later. I&amp;rsquo;ll be back in two shakes!!
. . .
And for you, just two lines of text!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, Aphrodite does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; seem to particularly want to work with me, and my tarot essentially told me &amp;ldquo;hey, two deities is enough, figure shit out with them first&amp;rdquo; sooo I&amp;rsquo;m gonna stick with that. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on moving my altar to a better and bigger spot so I can have enough space from both Freyja and The Morrigan. I did give a shot of whiskey to The Morrigan as an offering, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently waiting for her to let me know when she&amp;rsquo;s done with it (which I expect to just&amp;hellip; be my intuition telling me when lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="paganism---my-beliefs"&gt;Paganism - My Beliefs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I went to an event called &amp;ldquo;The Queer Artists Market&amp;rdquo; at Under The Umbrella Bookstore (an adorably gay local bookstore) where I bought a book of &amp;ldquo;Poetry as Spellcasting&amp;rdquo; (by Tamiko Beyer, Destiny Hemphill, &amp;amp; Lisbeth White) that I plan on using with both Freyja and The Morrigan, as well as TWO new tarot decks!! One of them is the Dark Days tarot by Wren Jane Brignac, and the This Might Hurt tarot by Isabella Rotman. They are both &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt; works of art and I am so excited to work with them! I have an older deck called the Crow Tarot by MJ Cullinane, which I use to communicate with The Morrigan (as the animal she loves and uses the most are crows and ravens). Right now I&amp;rsquo;m feeling the pull to use my This Might Hurt deck with Freyja, and the Dark Days deck when I need both deities or for any other readings unrelated to them. You might be wondering who these deities are and what they do&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="the-morrigan---the-great-queens"&gt;The Morrigan - The Great Queens
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friend has a hunch that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with The Morrigan for a while now and just didn&amp;rsquo;t know it, and I kind of believe her. The Morrigan is the goddess of war, fate, death, sovereignty, and prophecy. A lot of offerings to her involve setting a shot of whiskey on your altar for her, but also non-material things like reclaiming your sovereignty (in the words of John Beckett: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;They tell us who we’re supposed to be, then they sell us an identity. They keep us in fear so we’ll vote for them. They keep us outraged so we’ll keep watching and listening and clicking. We have to consciously and intentionally take back what is ours. &amp;hellip; Own your mind. Own your soul. Own your thoughts. Reclaim your sovereignty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;), as well as acts of social justice - something I have been doing for quite a few years now. This all includes donating hats and scarves I&amp;rsquo;ve crocheted to the local mutual-aid organization, giving my spare cash (that I purposely carry for this) to the homeless folks on my walks to school, and even going to a store just to buy soda for those same folks. Although I can&amp;rsquo;t currently go to protests, those are also included!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="freyja"&gt;Freyja
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Freyja is a goddess I had followed years ago, but unfortunately I let her down and had forgotten about her. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; forgotten her existence in my life, but I let other things get in the way and hold my attention. Freyja is the Norse goddess of love, beauty, fertility, war, wealth, and magic, and she is depicted being pulled in a chariot by large cats!! That was originally why I was pulled to her, but later realized it was for a more important purpose. In her, I have gained self-love and learned intentional self-care, as well as reigning in my anger issues and self-sabotaging actions. Now that I am back and getting into the groove of following Freyja, I plan on using make-up as a form of offering to her (because she is a goddess of beauty). Another offering idea I have is giving my cats fruits (strawberries. blueberries, black berries and raspberries!) which they love! I definitely need to write things down so I don&amp;rsquo;t always feel so lost or forgetful. I also need to earn Freyja&amp;rsquo;s trust again, because I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that my abandonment hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, this post has gotten quite long!! Thank you so much for reading, TTFN!!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First Post" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving 2025. It is 1:41pm and 55°F, which is wonderfully chilly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house with my husband and another friend, to spend Thanksgiving dinner with this friend and his family. &lt;br&gt;
I want to take a second to give space to all of the Native American tribes that were abused, murdered, kidnapped, and ultimately changed by settlers who took everything from Native people. You all deserve peace, to have your land back, and to have your languages back and your pre-colonial history not forgotten or erased. &lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t really celebrate Thanksgiving, because of its history. My only &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; is the excuse to see friends (like this friend) who I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get to see outside of special occasions and holidays, due to both parties being too busy on a normal basis. &lt;br&gt;
It feels like with adulthood comes the lack of care for holidays. I tried to hold onto it, the childhood magic that your family desperately holds onto for you and your cousins. However, growing up came with living across the country from the rest of your family, which then comes with never seeing your relatives (and never messaging or trying to see each other because neither of you seem to care at all), and over the years you end up feeling estranged from everyone. Thankfully I still keep up with one cousin and my younger brother, and they both keep up with me (and I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; thankful for them!) &lt;br&gt;
Anyways, this blog is going to be my way of processing life. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go to therapy yet, as my school schedule is so busy, but I know I still need to be responsible to myself and take care of my mental health. So, I will be talking about college and things I learn and struggle with, exciting things that happen (like how I was elected to the Unified Student Government), vacations, things with friends, drama, and personal things like how I saw a nutritionist and was told I was in &amp;ldquo;mild starvation&amp;rdquo; and how horrified I was. If you took the time to read all of this, thank you, and I hope you stick around for my other posts &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>