<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Health &amp; Wellness on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/categories/health--wellness/</link><description>Recent content in Health &amp; Wellness on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/categories/health--wellness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Note For Our Health</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/cover4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Note For Our Health" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="life-with-an-eating-disorder"&gt;Life With An Eating Disorder
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-it-happened"&gt;How It Happened
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It happened at some point between starting school and stopping my original anxiety medication abruptly. I had no choice, as my husband lost his job and the insurance with it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see a doctor or get emergency doses in my state. A few months after going cold-turkey from that medication, my anxiety started ramping up, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think straight, my mind was a mental prison, literally. Getting high made it worse, drinking made it worse, sleeping was my only relief but my mind wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me rest enough. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep a lid on the anxiety. My hand tingles: anxiety. My hearing rings: anxiety. &lt;em&gt;Everything&lt;/em&gt; set it off. So, eating wasn&amp;rsquo;t on my radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started with school, I started getting busy and walking more, to and from school, pride events, etc. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of an appetite, so I stopped eating full meals, and started eating less than half of a normal meal. At the worst of it, I was only eating 600 - 900 calories a day, when my baseline should be around 1200 calories. When I first moved to my college city, I weighed about 130 lbs. At the end of my eating disorder, I weighed only 108 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-it-hurt-me"&gt;How It Hurt Me
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time I felt shitty, my husband would always ask me, &amp;ldquo;Have you eaten enough? You need to eat.&amp;rdquo; The whole time, he knew it was getting worse, he knew how little I was eating. Almost daily, he would check in with me and see if I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten enough, he even got me an app to track my calorie intake. When I saw how little I was consuming, I cried to him, feeling so guilty for worrying him. I thought I was fine, that I was in control of it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel much different than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the heart issues started. I started getting palpitations almost a dozen times a day. One medication for IBS caused my heart to frequently send me to the ER. After I got off that medication, my heart stopped hitting 180bpm, but I would still get adreneline dumps in the middle of the night, or I&amp;rsquo;d have to lay down to equilise my blood pressure a couple times a day. I had no energy, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the heat of summer and almost got heat sickness any time I went camping (the heat never went above 90°). My husband and I went on a two week road trip up to the west coast, and I was so malnourished that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have energy to explore, bike, hike, or anything. I almost had no energy for sex. It was humiliating, and concerning. I thought my heart was giving me a million issues all of a sudden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-i-got-better"&gt;How I Got Better
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After seeing my cardiologist a second time, she suggested I see a nutritionist. Thankfully, she wasn&amp;rsquo;t booked out and I could see her within the week. And that appointment &lt;em&gt;crushed&lt;/em&gt; me. I gave her all the information, and my husband filled in the blanks &amp;ndash; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating fruits or veggies, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough meat. The nutritionist asked me if I ever had an eating disorder before, and that took me by surprise. She then told me, &amp;ldquo;You are in mild starvation right now. Any worse and your body will start failing you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I broke down. I was failing my body. I was failing myself. Worst of all, I was failing my husband, and I was making him scared for my health. We both cried over this appointment. He was scared for my health, for my safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a plan, and got to shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focused on high-calorie ready-to-eat and frozen meals, and I ordered a large amount of soylent meal-replacement smoothies. On top of that, we got a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of snacks, especially bread-y and fattening goodies, as that was something else I stopped eating completely. If you know me, you know I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; have a snack nearby, in my purse, etc. I never usually go without a snack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-im-doing-now"&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;m Doing Now
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so much better so quickly! I am currently 118 lbs, I have energy to walk, run, and explore things. I&amp;rsquo;m eating an almost perfectly balanced diet, and we&amp;rsquo;ve decided that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what kind of food I eat (fast food vs home-cooked) as long as I have color on my plate (meat, veggies, etc) and I&amp;rsquo;m eating at least 2/3 of each meal. Now, I am able to eat an entire McDonalds burger, or a whole 12-piece nugget from Chik-fil-a. I&amp;rsquo;m still not able to eat a whole fast food meal, with the entree and the fries, but I at least can finish the entire entree while eating a little bit of the side dish. I am also less picky about leftover meals, and can eat those whenever I feel hungry. I am also no longer having scary health issues! I rarely have heart palpitations, my heart doesn&amp;rsquo;t randomly race anymore, and I&amp;rsquo;m able to work out without getting dizzy and light-headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m proud of myself for getting my health back to where it should be. It was causing so much depression and distress for myself that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t physically or mentally handle doing the things I love. It&amp;rsquo;s so important that you figure out where your priorities lie, and if your health isn&amp;rsquo;t at the top of that list, you need to rearrange &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. We deserve to live a long, healthy, and &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt; life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodnight, ttfn 💖&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>