<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy New Year!!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/happy-new-year/cover5.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Happy New Year!!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="happy-new-year"&gt;HAPPY NEW YEAR!!!!!!!!!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi all!! I hope everyone reading this had a decent christmas and new year celebration (and if you chilled out like I did, I hope it was pleasant!) If you are a close friend or family member, you probably know I have been doing the Project 365 challenge on Instagram for the last 36 days! I did start early, but for some reason I felt like if I didn&amp;rsquo;t start during December, I would completely forget to do it for the new year (like my younger brother did! &lt;em&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m calling you out&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two challenges I want to stick to this year that are my top priority, and a couple others that aren&amp;rsquo;t as important. I&amp;rsquo;ve also started my sixth quarter in college, and all ten weeks are going to be jam-packed with five classes Monday through Thursday 8:30am till 5pm, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be waking up at 6am every morning&amp;hellip; 🫠 Thankfully, on Friday&amp;rsquo;s I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go to class until 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="new-quarter-new-me-bottom-priorities"&gt;New Quarter, New Me (Bottom Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My less-important priorities are for minor betterment. I want to wear makeup and fun-style earrings more often! And I have been, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to feel bad about it or think I look bad for forgetting or being too lazy. I am also going to try to hold myself somewhat accountable for learning outside of school; This includes learning Spanish, getting better at understanding and writing code, and learning about data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been (as I mentioned) posting to Instagram everyday for the Project 365 challenge. This isn&amp;rsquo;t typically important, but it is helping me be more present in my life and the lives of people that want to know me. For the last couple days, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to quickly take a random snapshot of something unimportant to my day, simply because I keep doomscrolling on TikTok and Instagram reels. I took a look at my watch-time on Tiktok, and my average for December is around 3.5 hours (at least one full week could be put together of days spent 5 hours on Tiktok alone), and I can feel my brain slowly rotting. I want to do better, I want better for myself, and I want to be present in my own life. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend my days sitting on my couch drowning in my phone. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the end result will be my going out with friends, on dates with my husband, and spending time outdoors with camping, hiking, or even just sitting in a park while I read or crochet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="resolutions-or-whatever-top-priorities"&gt;Resolutions, Or Whatever (Top Priorities)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sooo there&amp;rsquo;s a reading challenge I found via &amp;lsquo;jananie&amp;rsquo; called The Anti-Brain-Rot Challenge!! It&amp;rsquo;s based around building consistency, forming your own opinions, and consuming media mindfully. Here are all the rules of this challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="building-consistency"&gt;Building Consistency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read for at least one 45 minute session per day, where you (optionally) annotate what you read. This includes physical books, e-books, and audio books. This helps you hit that mindful consumption goal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; article or essay per month on any topic that interests you. These can be academic essays, news articles, or even a blog like this one! For advanced challengers, you can read one article or essay &lt;em&gt;per week&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book by a BIPOC author for every book you read by a white author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mindfully-consume-media"&gt;Mindfully Consume Media
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; genre&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Literary fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Historical fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science Fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Romance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; History or Political&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Memoir or Biography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from the following &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A play&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A graphic novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; An anthology or short story collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A translated book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Read at least &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; book from each of the following &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a queer main character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book with a disability representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an author NOT from North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a black author who is &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an indigenous author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a SWANA (Southwest Asian and North African) author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a latin author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by an east Asian author that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Chinese, Japanese, or Korean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; A book by a south Asian author who is not Indian&lt;br&gt;
Thankfully, each requirement doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to match &lt;em&gt;each individual book&lt;/em&gt;, we can have multiple requirements in &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; book! That will make this challenge much less daunting!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="thinking-critically--forming-your-own-opinions"&gt;Thinking Critically / Forming Your Own Opinions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Create your own critical media journal: write down notes or reviews on each book you read, each movie or show you watch, and each article or essay you read. I will be doing this here, and (if I have a lot to say) I may make a whole blog post about my reviews!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big thing I want to prioritize this year is excersize. I want to not only grow a phat ass (lol) but I want functional strength. I want my hips to support me better and not hurt from simply walking, and I especially want stronger shoulders that don&amp;rsquo;t crack and pop with every movement, and I want to be able to lift almost anything above my shoulders (which, the heaviest things I can lift &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; are my 10lb cats).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found this guy David (movementwithdavid on IG) whose favorite excersize is &lt;em&gt;functional movement and stretches&lt;/em&gt;! I have a few videos of his that are based around the hips, arms, and shoulders and how to keep them mobile and strong. I definitely plan on referencing his content as needed for my workouts! My main goal for working out is to avoid any severe decline in my mobility. I want to be the old lady who struts around the park with flare, instead of the old lady who has been relying on a walker since the moment she turned 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to find attainable goals for yourself! Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a small or large change, any positive change is &lt;em&gt;GOOD&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, I gotta pay attention in class. TTFN!! 😃&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Note For Our Health</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/a-note-for-our-health/cover4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Note For Our Health" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="life-with-an-eating-disorder"&gt;Life With An Eating Disorder
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-it-happened"&gt;How It Happened
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It happened at some point between starting school and stopping my original anxiety medication abruptly. I had no choice, as my husband lost his job and the insurance with it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see a doctor or get emergency doses in my state. A few months after going cold-turkey from that medication, my anxiety started ramping up, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think straight, my mind was a mental prison, literally. Getting high made it worse, drinking made it worse, sleeping was my only relief but my mind wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me rest enough. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep a lid on the anxiety. My hand tingles: anxiety. My hearing rings: anxiety. &lt;em&gt;Everything&lt;/em&gt; set it off. So, eating wasn&amp;rsquo;t on my radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started with school, I started getting busy and walking more, to and from school, pride events, etc. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of an appetite, so I stopped eating full meals, and started eating less than half of a normal meal. At the worst of it, I was only eating 600 - 900 calories a day, when my baseline should be around 1200 calories. When I first moved to my college city, I weighed about 130 lbs. At the end of my eating disorder, I weighed only 108 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-it-hurt-me"&gt;How It Hurt Me
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time I felt shitty, my husband would always ask me, &amp;ldquo;Have you eaten enough? You need to eat.&amp;rdquo; The whole time, he knew it was getting worse, he knew how little I was eating. Almost daily, he would check in with me and see if I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten enough, he even got me an app to track my calorie intake. When I saw how little I was consuming, I cried to him, feeling so guilty for worrying him. I thought I was fine, that I was in control of it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel much different than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the heart issues started. I started getting palpitations almost a dozen times a day. One medication for IBS caused my heart to frequently send me to the ER. After I got off that medication, my heart stopped hitting 180bpm, but I would still get adreneline dumps in the middle of the night, or I&amp;rsquo;d have to lay down to equilise my blood pressure a couple times a day. I had no energy, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the heat of summer and almost got heat sickness any time I went camping (the heat never went above 90°). My husband and I went on a two week road trip up to the west coast, and I was so malnourished that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have energy to explore, bike, hike, or anything. I almost had no energy for sex. It was humiliating, and concerning. I thought my heart was giving me a million issues all of a sudden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-i-got-better"&gt;How I Got Better
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After seeing my cardiologist a second time, she suggested I see a nutritionist. Thankfully, she wasn&amp;rsquo;t booked out and I could see her within the week. And that appointment &lt;em&gt;crushed&lt;/em&gt; me. I gave her all the information, and my husband filled in the blanks &amp;ndash; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating fruits or veggies, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating enough meat. The nutritionist asked me if I ever had an eating disorder before, and that took me by surprise. She then told me, &amp;ldquo;You are in mild starvation right now. Any worse and your body will start failing you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I broke down. I was failing my body. I was failing myself. Worst of all, I was failing my husband, and I was making him scared for my health. We both cried over this appointment. He was scared for my health, for my safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a plan, and got to shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focused on high-calorie ready-to-eat and frozen meals, and I ordered a large amount of soylent meal-replacement smoothies. On top of that, we got a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of snacks, especially bread-y and fattening goodies, as that was something else I stopped eating completely. If you know me, you know I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; have a snack nearby, in my purse, etc. I never usually go without a snack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-im-doing-now"&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;m Doing Now
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so much better so quickly! I am currently 118 lbs, I have energy to walk, run, and explore things. I&amp;rsquo;m eating an almost perfectly balanced diet, and we&amp;rsquo;ve decided that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what kind of food I eat (fast food vs home-cooked) as long as I have color on my plate (meat, veggies, etc) and I&amp;rsquo;m eating at least 2/3 of each meal. Now, I am able to eat an entire McDonalds burger, or a whole 12-piece nugget from Chik-fil-a. I&amp;rsquo;m still not able to eat a whole fast food meal, with the entree and the fries, but I at least can finish the entire entree while eating a little bit of the side dish. I am also less picky about leftover meals, and can eat those whenever I feel hungry. I am also no longer having scary health issues! I rarely have heart palpitations, my heart doesn&amp;rsquo;t randomly race anymore, and I&amp;rsquo;m able to work out without getting dizzy and light-headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m proud of myself for getting my health back to where it should be. It was causing so much depression and distress for myself that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t physically or mentally handle doing the things I love. It&amp;rsquo;s so important that you figure out where your priorities lie, and if your health isn&amp;rsquo;t at the top of that list, you need to rearrange &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. We deserve to live a long, healthy, and &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt; life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodnight, ttfn 💖&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Christmas Vacation So Far!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/cover3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Christmas Vacation So Far!" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-vacation-so-far"&gt;My Vacation So Far
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hellooooo!!! It&amp;rsquo;s been a hot minute since my last post, I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely been allowing myself the time to be lazy (and allowing things to pile up so I have more interesting things to talk about). To be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s been nice! I&amp;rsquo;m allowed to relax and not take too much seriously. The last couple days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been vegging out on the couch with one of my roommates binging &lt;em&gt;True Blood&lt;/em&gt; while she plays &lt;em&gt;Skyrim&lt;/em&gt; and I knit. Except knitting isn&amp;rsquo;t going too well, because the damn hat I&amp;rsquo;m working on isn&amp;rsquo;t getting smaller while I decrease the stitches, which is getting annoying&amp;hellip; But I guess I should count the stitches I have now and actually make sure there are less than I started with. Anywho!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="packing-and-moving"&gt;Packing and Moving
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned previously that my husband and I will be moving into a house with two of my school friends, and we found a store with cardboard boxes! They sell small boxes for $1, medium for $1.50, and large boxes (which are huge) for $1.75, so it was a friggin steal! Right now the boxes I got are sitting in the truck bed until I grab our hand-truck to bring them inside, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get all the small crap I&amp;rsquo;ve collected over the last couple years organized and into boxes! Also, while I&amp;rsquo;ve started slowly packing, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to figure out where all of my crystals went to and wrap them up all nice in the bubble wrap! The last thing I want is to break even more crystals 😅 One roommate already broke my mini-penis fluorite crystal (it was in a bad spot, and he yeeted it onto the floor with a cable). Now he owes me a new mini-penis! 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="paganism---my-altar"&gt;Paganism - My Altar
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of packing and finding things.. Since roommate A has moved into our apartment (while we wait to find a house), she is also a practicing pagan, we&amp;rsquo;ve bonded over that and have both set up separate altars on my media center! Here&amp;rsquo;s mine:
&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar.jpg"
width="3024"
height="3024"
srcset="https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar_hu_e2c7a33124342d67.jpg 480w, https://melblogs.online/p/christmas-vacation-so-far/altar_hu_c9246ee81edddee7.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="My Alter To The Morrigan, Freyja, and Aphrodite"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
&gt;
Here I have my altar (keeping A&amp;rsquo;s altar private), where I have dedicated space to The Morrigan, Freyja, and Aphrodite. I spent time with my Crow Tarot deck to see if The Morrigan and Freyja want to work with me, and their responses were quite apt. The Morrigan said I need to quit being lazy and get a hold on my anger (which has come up once again because I&amp;rsquo;m not used to dealing with not-so-mature brains who can&amp;rsquo;t handle my overly sarcastic remarks&amp;hellip;which can be mean to people who don&amp;rsquo;t know me well enough, or people who are especially sensitive in a specfic moment), but she is still willing to work with me as long as I am active in my devotion. Freyja I have already worked with in my past, before I became too lazy and forgotten our relationship. Her tarot reading told me I need more patience in my everyday life, which I agree with, and trying to keep a pin on to hold myself accountable. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet done a reading for Aphrodite, which I feel sorry for. I&amp;rsquo;m about to work out with roommate A and then shower, so I can be clean for Aphrodite&amp;rsquo;s reading later. I&amp;rsquo;ll be back in two shakes!!
. . .
And for you, just two lines of text!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, Aphrodite does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; seem to particularly want to work with me, and my tarot essentially told me &amp;ldquo;hey, two deities is enough, figure shit out with them first&amp;rdquo; sooo I&amp;rsquo;m gonna stick with that. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on moving my altar to a better and bigger spot so I can have enough space from both Freyja and The Morrigan. I did give a shot of whiskey to The Morrigan as an offering, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently waiting for her to let me know when she&amp;rsquo;s done with it (which I expect to just&amp;hellip; be my intuition telling me when lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="paganism---my-beliefs"&gt;Paganism - My Beliefs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I went to an event called &amp;ldquo;The Queer Artists Market&amp;rdquo; at Under The Umbrella Bookstore (an adorably gay local bookstore) where I bought a book of &amp;ldquo;Poetry as Spellcasting&amp;rdquo; (by Tamiko Beyer, Destiny Hemphill, &amp;amp; Lisbeth White) that I plan on using with both Freyja and The Morrigan, as well as TWO new tarot decks!! One of them is the Dark Days tarot by Wren Jane Brignac, and the This Might Hurt tarot by Isabella Rotman. They are both &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt; works of art and I am so excited to work with them! I have an older deck called the Crow Tarot by MJ Cullinane, which I use to communicate with The Morrigan (as the animal she loves and uses the most are crows and ravens). Right now I&amp;rsquo;m feeling the pull to use my This Might Hurt deck with Freyja, and the Dark Days deck when I need both deities or for any other readings unrelated to them. You might be wondering who these deities are and what they do&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="the-morrigan---the-great-queens"&gt;The Morrigan - The Great Queens
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friend has a hunch that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with The Morrigan for a while now and just didn&amp;rsquo;t know it, and I kind of believe her. The Morrigan is the goddess of war, fate, death, sovereignty, and prophecy. A lot of offerings to her involve setting a shot of whiskey on your altar for her, but also non-material things like reclaiming your sovereignty (in the words of John Beckett: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;They tell us who we’re supposed to be, then they sell us an identity. They keep us in fear so we’ll vote for them. They keep us outraged so we’ll keep watching and listening and clicking. We have to consciously and intentionally take back what is ours. &amp;hellip; Own your mind. Own your soul. Own your thoughts. Reclaim your sovereignty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;), as well as acts of social justice - something I have been doing for quite a few years now. This all includes donating hats and scarves I&amp;rsquo;ve crocheted to the local mutual-aid organization, giving my spare cash (that I purposely carry for this) to the homeless folks on my walks to school, and even going to a store just to buy soda for those same folks. Although I can&amp;rsquo;t currently go to protests, those are also included!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="freyja"&gt;Freyja
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Freyja is a goddess I had followed years ago, but unfortunately I let her down and had forgotten about her. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; forgotten her existence in my life, but I let other things get in the way and hold my attention. Freyja is the Norse goddess of love, beauty, fertility, war, wealth, and magic, and she is depicted being pulled in a chariot by large cats!! That was originally why I was pulled to her, but later realized it was for a more important purpose. In her, I have gained self-love and learned intentional self-care, as well as reigning in my anger issues and self-sabotaging actions. Now that I am back and getting into the groove of following Freyja, I plan on using make-up as a form of offering to her (because she is a goddess of beauty). Another offering idea I have is giving my cats fruits (strawberries. blueberries, black berries and raspberries!) which they love! I definitely need to write things down so I don&amp;rsquo;t always feel so lost or forgetful. I also need to earn Freyja&amp;rsquo;s trust again, because I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that my abandonment hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, this post has gotten quite long!! Thank you so much for reading, TTFN!!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Drama Llama!</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/drama-llama/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/drama-llama/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/drama-llama/cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Drama Llama!" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="oh-the-drama"&gt;Oh, The Drama!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alright, now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had a healthy discussion with my husband and we both had our mini-mental-breakdowns, we&amp;rsquo;re both feeling more level-headed. I also apologize to you, Dear Reader, for my very random outburst; Our apartment is incredibly cluttered and FULL of everyones crap, and it is getting all of us to a breaking point. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to my two friends, and they&amp;rsquo;ve agreed that this week we will all do a small part to help tidy up the main living space, and once this week is over, we will all start condensing all of our stuff into storage and give ourselves as much space as possible. We have until the end of February to live in this tiny apartment, so we&amp;rsquo;ve gotta make our lives as easy as possible, and keep the negative effects on our mental health as little as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we are SO CLOSE to finishing our quarter!! We are all SO tired, and SO excited to be done. Today, we are finishing our separate project presentations for one class, and we&amp;rsquo;ve all finished our exams, so after today we&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing to work on!! Yippeeeee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="a-change-of-topic---my-childhood-vs-me-today"&gt;A Change Of Topic - My Childhood VS Me Today
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does my current lifestyle reflect my childhood?&lt;/strong&gt;
Short answer: hell no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longer answer? My current lifestyle is full of love, respect, communication, and education thanks to amazing friends and my found family. I mainly have my husband to thank for the early-lifestyle change; He encouraged me to go back to therapy, taught me what proper healthy communication looks and sounds like. Thanks to him, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that when I am frustrated, overstimulated, or angry with someone or something, I am allowed to step away and cool off and I deserve uninterruption. The &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; person in my life that has disrespected this boundary is my mother, and she is no longer in my life. Over the last ten years, I have been working to perfect my communication skills and keeping a level head, I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten into any painful arguments with anyone. Any time my husband and I, or any of my friends or siblings and I, have some miscommunications or hurt feelings, we all feel safe enough to approach each other for a calm and meaningful discussion to get back on the same page and resolve any lingering tension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also made a lot of friends, people who share my experiences as a child and teenager and have similar mental illnesses. These friends have taught me so much, and helped me recognize my toxic patterns, and also helped me see the value in myself. They taught me what boundaries are important, and how to uphold them safely. Because I was able to create and uphold my boundaries, I was able to disown my mother, and I don&amp;rsquo;t visit my family often in order to avoid triggering my anger and anxiety. As a child, I was bullied quite harshly by not only school kids, but by my older siblings and mother. Today, I have such strong boundaries that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t phase me if anyone tries to bully me as an adult, instead I either shut them down, or I allow it to go over my head and ignore it. However, if someone I care about is getting bullied, I immediately get active with it (which is made easier by being actively in college). I tell any advisors of the situation and keep track of it and on their case until it gets resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s another thing &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m in college!! My second year out of 3 at that. Younger me &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; thought this was going to happen; Strictly because I was told by family members that I would never get this far, I would always be a failure. Thanks to a safer and healthier environment, I know that that isn&amp;rsquo;t true. I&amp;rsquo;ve succeeded in areas that those people could never reach (and only because they would never let themselves get that far). I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much, and I&amp;rsquo;m thankful I was able to find anxiety medication when I did&amp;hellip; My memory is getting better, along with my self-confidence. I&amp;rsquo;m able to memorize things I code and learn better, and during my three week break I&amp;rsquo;m going to be learning how to use React and NextJS, which I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to specialize in, along with Typescript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what else to write about regarding this 😅 If you stayed to read this far, thank you!! I&amp;rsquo;ll see you next time :)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Today Kinda Sucks</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/today-kinda-sucks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/today-kinda-sucks/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/today-kinda-sucks/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Today Kinda Sucks" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="just-today"&gt;Just Today
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today started out pretty good, me and two friends went on a day trip to pick up some things that my friends needed. Then I helped one of them pack up their stuff from their school apartment and bring it to my place (we&amp;rsquo;ll be putting most of it in storage this week). I packed up almost all of my yarn except for the bits I think I&amp;rsquo;d use between now and February, which is when my husband, my two friends, and I move into a hopefully not expensive house together to save costs for all of us. All of us being in one 900sqft apartment has taught me that getting overstimulated is a lot easier, and that my mental health isn&amp;rsquo;t as good as I thought it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="borderline-personality-disorder"&gt;Borderline Personality Disorder
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have BPD; Not bi-polar, but borderline. People who have BPD usually get it through complex-PSTD, which I also have. That C-PTSD usually stems from childhood abuse and/or neglect, which I went through. How does this tie in to things today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ties in by affecting my originally great and fun mood and tanking it down to the floor with the flip of a switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, this happened because of a mix of things. One friend was being too stupid and goofy under the influence, poking me and poking my pimple and being clingy, I was overwhelmed with how much shit is suddenly in our apartment taking up space, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my husband doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand how these two friends and I treat each other (because he isn&amp;rsquo;t with us all day at school) so he contantly, and seriously, keeps telling me I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;being too hard&amp;rdquo; on them and I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;being too mean/ too much&amp;rdquo; to them. So, thanks to BPD, I am not only resenting my husband because of his blind bullshit, but he&amp;rsquo;s making me resent having my friends as friends. I resent giving up my daybed for my friends to sleep in because now I can&amp;rsquo;t have a night alone to cool off and get away from &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m seriously considering sleeping in my car tonight, damn the consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as a way of coping with these feelings, I am alone in my bedroom until everyone goes to bed and my husband comes into the bedroom and we inevitably have a chat, writing this blog post. Here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping it helps, because so far nothing&amp;rsquo;s changed and I still want to cry and fight everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways. goodnight.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>This Week and Its Many Issues</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/this-weeks-issues/cover5.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This Week and Its Many Issues" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="day-so-far"&gt;Day So Far
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello and holy shit it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; Thursday&amp;hellip; It has been a WEEK and the damn things not even over yet. I&amp;rsquo;ve had to stay up past midnight 3 nights in a row when my bedtime is 10pm, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been running on 6ish hours of sleep for three days. I am finally all caught up on each assignment (thank goodness I wasn&amp;rsquo;t that far behind)! However, crunch time hasn&amp;rsquo;t ended and won&amp;rsquo;t end until around December 11th or 12th. I have a breakfast meeting with the president of my school for the USG meeting at freaking 9AM tomorrow morning, which means I don&amp;rsquo;t get to sleep in like usual. Then I have calculus in the afternoon for an hour. THEN I get to relax and study until a USG team bonding event at 6pm which could go on past 9pm. Then I have my math exam at 1pm Saturday. 🫠 My anxiety meds are the only reason why I haven&amp;rsquo;t given up at this current point of exhaustion. It&amp;rsquo;s 7:22pm right now, and I definitely think I&amp;rsquo;m going to shower soon and get to bed by 10pm again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="calculus"&gt;Calculus
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sooo&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m failing calculus!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m already weak with math in general, but calculus is a whole new demon. Even my three smartest classmates keep getting confused and stuck on these problems. I haven&amp;rsquo;t given up, but I do only have one week left, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to shift my focus to my other classes, as well as setting myself up with an online calculus course that will be overall cheaper than a weekly tutoring session. Now that I at least have some calculus under my belt, I know I&amp;rsquo;m at least going to have better luck this time around. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this online course because my student advocate suggested it, and she said if I complete the course with a passing grade, I can easily transfer the credits and I won&amp;rsquo;t have to retake the class at all! I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly grateful for her, she understands and told me that this is one of the three most failed courses (english comp and educational learning theories being the other two.. because students are lazy as hell). I was pretty broken up about failing this class, but it&amp;rsquo;s comforting to know that it won&amp;rsquo;t effect the rest of my degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="english-comp"&gt;English Comp
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a research paper about billionaires and their effect on the environment, as well as how technology can help slow climate change AND hold billionaires accountable. Did you know, there is a technology called Blockchain that hosts software that can track corporations and companies carbon emissions, and they get &amp;ldquo;carbon credits&amp;rdquo; when they hit their carbon emisson reduction goals?? That&amp;rsquo;s freaking awesome! There was also a satellite called the MethaneSAT, which would view the Earth and track the source of carbon emissions, and track &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; was emitting the most carbon and methane!! Technology is freaking amazing, and I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful for the opportunity to become a software engineer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho&amp;hellip;.. It&amp;rsquo;s 11:15pm and past my bedtime :D yippeeeee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Image Owned By &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fkr.pinterest.com%2Fpin%2F122160208638550196%2F&amp;psig=AOvVaw2Kn71TAIM6oTf6w1ffYF7j&amp;ust=1764919783593000&amp;source=images&amp;cd=vfe&amp;opi=89978449&amp;ved=0CBUQjhxqFwoTCJDo7t20o5EDFQAAAAAdAAAAABAE"&gt;The Gypsy Goddess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/cover4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="days-so-far"&gt;Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="sunday-nov-30"&gt;Sunday, Nov 30
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello again! Yesterday was a particularly relaxing day; We all woke up to snow and sleet, and 33°F, barely breezy! Definitely too cold for a bike ride. Productivity was low, but laundry got half done (still gotta fold it&amp;hellip;), dishes got done (thank you, hubby!) and the blog was edited. I started learning how to knit after I&amp;rsquo;ve been crocheting for the last five years, and I honestly love it so far! I got myself used to casting the yarn onto the needles, creating a &amp;ldquo;magic join&amp;rdquo; so I can work in the round, and I am now making my first hat! It is taking some time, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it will still be faster than using crochet. With this new skill, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping making things like hats, socks, and sweaters will be easier and faster than crocheting them (also, crochet socks &lt;em&gt;SUUUCK&lt;/em&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="monday-dec-1"&gt;Monday, Dec 1
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="shout-out-to-big-sis"&gt;Shout Out to Big Sis!!
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I feel like a jackass, I forgot my older sisters friggin BIRTHDAY yesterday!!! 😭 I am &lt;strong&gt;SO&lt;/strong&gt; sorry, big sis!!! I think she turned 40 this year&amp;hellip; I turn 30 next year, gosh I feel old as hell. I also want to shout out this same sister, because I was thinking about our childhood a couple days ago. We didn&amp;rsquo;t always get along, but she never failed to support me and make me feel loved. I never felt alone with her. I remember when she would do my makeup and curl my hair for my school chorus concerts and school dances. She never made me feel like I was a burden, or like she hated me for it. Sis, I hope you see this, and I want you to know that I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for you. You made me feel beautiful when my bullies made me feel ugly, and you took care of me even though you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had to. You were also just a kid back then. I love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="today-at-school"&gt;Today At School
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m back at school after a 4 day weekend from thanksgiving, and today I have Developing Scalable Weeb Applications, where we learn how to connect our code projects to a database and use SQL in our code to help us build and modify the data in our database. I also have Calculus, Intro to English Comp, and Web-Based Software Projects, which ends at 8pm each night. Most of these classes I like, especially the last class. It&amp;rsquo;s a project class where we work on teams of three to create a web-based application using a database. My team is currently working to create a webapp similar to the OG twitter, but for shower thoughts! No pictures, no videos, no threads&amp;hellip; Only posts, reactions, and maybe replies! I am very excited for the end product, and I will make sure to post screenshots when it&amp;rsquo;s done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also a member of my schools Unified Student Government (yippee!!!) as a Senator. Today we discussed student initiatives, and thanks to my suggestion we are soon getting a brand new refridgerator dedicated for the students! WOO! Finally we won&amp;rsquo;t have to compete with the school clubs and activites for fridge space. We also discussed ways to encourage third-year students to actually show up to their internships (because TWO companies backed out of working with our school due to so many students not showing up). So far our ideas are to create large posters to put at least a couple on each floor (it&amp;rsquo;s a very small school), and have a QR code for students to see &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the internships are about about, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they work, and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they are so important (our careers quite literally rely on it). But we&amp;rsquo;ll see how well that goes over, or whether these lazy bunch of students will ruin a good thing &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; for the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news"&gt;World News
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="ad-fatigue"&gt;Ad Fatigue
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video on Tiktok about ad fatigue, oh my GOODNESS I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; damn tired of ALL the ads!!! &lt;strong&gt;Everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;!!! Instagram and Pinterest are especially egregious, Pinterest you can&amp;rsquo;t even tell what&amp;rsquo;s an ad and what&amp;rsquo;s a post, and every time you try to scroll you end up triggering a random ad to go to its link. On Instagram, almost every other post is some sort of ad, and &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; every 2 reels videos is one or two ads. Luckily, tiktok ads are (for now) relatively easy to get rid of, and my husband and I pay for Youtube Premium so no ads there (and he found an extension that blocks promotions inside each video on our TVs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, why the hell am I getting marketing emails for companies I&amp;rsquo;ve either never heard of or don&amp;rsquo;t have an account with?? It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that hitting &amp;ldquo;unubscribe&amp;rdquo; from the majority of these emails doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Oh yeah, this also happens because your email gets sold. So that&amp;rsquo;s freaking &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Black Friday also isn&amp;rsquo;t the same thing it was when I was a child, not even a full 20 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole month long debacle where sales only go up to a regular 40% when it used to go up to 80% or 90%. Companies (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Target, Michaels, and Amazon) are even faking sales, where they hike up the price and make the sale price match the &lt;em&gt;original damn price!!!&lt;/em&gt; People are already boycotting these companies (as they damn well should) and soon it&amp;rsquo;s going to bite the rich in the ass (Target and Starbucks are already feeling the pain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The lines between being a human being and being a brand are so blurred that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to distinguish between the two.&amp;rdquo; Hannah Glenn&amp;rsquo;s (@hannahglennhannahglenn on tiktok) recent video is why I decided to write on this topic. She talks about how nothing in life feels like an authentic experience anymore, and I wholeheartedly agree. From making friends and going out to hang, to watching your favorite creator on your platform of choice. Every time someone creates a good new thing, they end up getting a hard on for the concept of capitalism and making even a tiiiiiny bit more money through ad revenue. You can&amp;rsquo;t even go on a nice walk anymore without seeing at a minimum of one influencer &lt;em&gt;per walk outside&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d be surprised if smaller countries didn&amp;rsquo;t start banning the act of influencing because of the sheer amount of assholery that these weirdos perform just to get a few extra clicks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen way too many videos of influencers getting dragged online for abusing waitstaff or killing homeless people in the name of a &amp;ldquo;joke&amp;rdquo; (fuck you, Nat Reynolds, you don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to forget even though you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;only human&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho. I gotta get started on my project class&amp;rsquo; work. TTFN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you know me personally and read this far, let me know if there&amp;rsquo;s anything you want me to talk about from my perspective! ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Image Owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.freepik.com%2Ffree-photos-vectors%2Fabstract-gradient-background&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDHAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;FreePik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Life, Media, and What Matters</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/life-media-and-what-matters/cover3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Life, Media, and What Matters" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="my-last-3-days-so-far"&gt;My Last 3 Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, all! &lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s a new day, and this is my first post post-thanksgiving (hehe)! I slept pretty badly last night (as per the last few nights) but I got to take a 2 hour nap, and was then invited on a bike ride with my husband and our roommate D! This was D&amp;rsquo;s first time riding a road bike specifically, and to be honest, he did just fine. He was especially nervous about riding with drop handlebars, but over the weeks I guess he&amp;rsquo;d gotten used to the idea, and he did awesome! It was funny though, I was leading the trail with D behind me and my husband at the back (because he&amp;rsquo;s the fastest and most experienced), and about 3 times D had either fallen into a chain-link fence (which saved him from &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; falling) or he hand nearly fallen but caught himself, and all of this happened because he was going too slow while waiting for me to go ahead of him&amp;hellip; lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anywho! We also stopped at the local skate park/ shop nearby, after finding out on Instagram that a local mutual aid organization is collecting winter clothing and survival items for our homeless community, and dropped off seven fluffy crochet beanies I made earlier this year. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to make more, and I might make a couple warm blankets or mittens and scarves. Last thing we did together today was stop at Trek to buy D a helmet that fits (he&amp;rsquo;s got a pretty thick noggin), and grab food at the mall on our way home. D, by the way, is unofficially our roommate, as he and another friend will be moving in with us in a couple months. So tonight, D stayed back at their place to play games with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="class-research---billionaires-suck"&gt;Class Research - Billionaires Suck
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just got done doing research on how to hold billionaires accountable to slow down the climate crisis, and successfully found &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; reliable papers&amp;hellip; I might have to expand my research juuuust a touch. Thankfully my calculus homework is done minus the very last question, and yes I do in fact still hate math (you can&amp;rsquo;t convince me to like it, I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with anti-derivatives). I am officially mostly caught up on homework! If I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned it yet, I am a 29 year old college student in my second year of college, I have two best friends who are 10 years younger (yes, it&amp;rsquo;s weird, and yes, I have communicated that unequal power dynamics make me super uncomfy, they have agreed to let me know if things change in a bad way) and my degree is software engineering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="a-late-intro"&gt;A Late Intro
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am also a part of the LGBTQ community, I go by they/them pronouns, and I feel a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; strong sense of justice! If human rights, animals, the LGBTQ, respecting insects, and our climate crisis don&amp;rsquo;t align with your beliefs, then we will not appreciate each other and you are not welcome to continue reading (although I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news---palestine"&gt;World News - Palestine
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of world-news, have you heard the new movie / documentary coming out? It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The Voice of Hind Rajab&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched it past the trailor, and I still cried. I remember vividly when the news of her murder came out, what those people had put her through. Wesam Rajab, Hind&amp;rsquo;s mother, has become an advocate for the children of Gaza who all have died, or are dying and fearing for their lives. All children deserve to be free of the fate that was forced onto Hind. And NO, there is no such thing as Palistinians being trained soldiers from &lt;em&gt;literal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;birth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. That is what the people YOU hate want you to believe, and you&amp;rsquo;re straight falling for it. Anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="us-news---mmiw"&gt;US News - MMIW
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, in American news, &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-admin-removes-report-on-missing-native-americans-11063830" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;the Trump admin removed an important report on MMIW&lt;/a&gt;. MMIW means &amp;ldquo;Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women [and children]. The report is called Not One More, and the senator who was part of the commitee to introduce the 2020 Not Invisible Act had noticed it disappeared from the DOJ&amp;rsquo;s website. This is huge, because not only is MMIW a very ignored American crisis, but it just shows that this Admin &lt;em&gt;does not care about the MMIW crisis&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, a DOJ spokesperson was quoted saying the report was removed to &amp;ldquo;ensure compliance&amp;rdquo; to an executive order, which then states &amp;ldquo;women are biologically female, and men are biologically male.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;What that has to do with MMIW, I have no fucking idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, not only are Native Americans and Native Alaskans still being politically abused and ignored, but they&amp;rsquo;re quickly being erased in a violent way. This will allow &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; Indigenous women and children to go missing and/or turn up murdered, and no one will be forced to care, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should all be angry about this. Goodnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Photo owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstock.adobe.com%2Fsearch%3Fk%3Dgradient%2Bcover&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDiAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;Adobe Stock Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First Post" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving 2025. It is 1:41pm and 55°F, which is wonderfully chilly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house with my husband and another friend, to spend Thanksgiving dinner with this friend and his family. &lt;br&gt;
I want to take a second to give space to all of the Native American tribes that were abused, murdered, kidnapped, and ultimately changed by settlers who took everything from Native people. You all deserve peace, to have your land back, and to have your languages back and your pre-colonial history not forgotten or erased. &lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t really celebrate Thanksgiving, because of its history. My only &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; is the excuse to see friends (like this friend) who I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get to see outside of special occasions and holidays, due to both parties being too busy on a normal basis. &lt;br&gt;
It feels like with adulthood comes the lack of care for holidays. I tried to hold onto it, the childhood magic that your family desperately holds onto for you and your cousins. However, growing up came with living across the country from the rest of your family, which then comes with never seeing your relatives (and never messaging or trying to see each other because neither of you seem to care at all), and over the years you end up feeling estranged from everyone. Thankfully I still keep up with one cousin and my younger brother, and they both keep up with me (and I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; thankful for them!) &lt;br&gt;
Anyways, this blog is going to be my way of processing life. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go to therapy yet, as my school schedule is so busy, but I know I still need to be responsible to myself and take care of my mental health. So, I will be talking about college and things I learn and struggle with, exciting things that happen (like how I was elected to the Unified Student Government), vacations, things with friends, drama, and personal things like how I saw a nutritionist and was told I was in &amp;ldquo;mild starvation&amp;rdquo; and how horrified I was. If you took the time to read all of this, thank you, and I hope you stick around for my other posts &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>