<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Capitalism on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/tags/capitalism/</link><description>Recent content in Capitalism on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/tags/capitalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/mixed-bag/cover4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mixed Bag, Sunday &amp; Mostly Monday" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="days-so-far"&gt;Days So Far
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="sunday-nov-30"&gt;Sunday, Nov 30
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello again! Yesterday was a particularly relaxing day; We all woke up to snow and sleet, and 33°F, barely breezy! Definitely too cold for a bike ride. Productivity was low, but laundry got half done (still gotta fold it&amp;hellip;), dishes got done (thank you, hubby!) and the blog was edited. I started learning how to knit after I&amp;rsquo;ve been crocheting for the last five years, and I honestly love it so far! I got myself used to casting the yarn onto the needles, creating a &amp;ldquo;magic join&amp;rdquo; so I can work in the round, and I am now making my first hat! It is taking some time, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it will still be faster than using crochet. With this new skill, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping making things like hats, socks, and sweaters will be easier and faster than crocheting them (also, crochet socks &lt;em&gt;SUUUCK&lt;/em&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="monday-dec-1"&gt;Monday, Dec 1
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="shout-out-to-big-sis"&gt;Shout Out to Big Sis!!
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I feel like a jackass, I forgot my older sisters friggin BIRTHDAY yesterday!!! 😭 I am &lt;strong&gt;SO&lt;/strong&gt; sorry, big sis!!! I think she turned 40 this year&amp;hellip; I turn 30 next year, gosh I feel old as hell. I also want to shout out this same sister, because I was thinking about our childhood a couple days ago. We didn&amp;rsquo;t always get along, but she never failed to support me and make me feel loved. I never felt alone with her. I remember when she would do my makeup and curl my hair for my school chorus concerts and school dances. She never made me feel like I was a burden, or like she hated me for it. Sis, I hope you see this, and I want you to know that I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for you. You made me feel beautiful when my bullies made me feel ugly, and you took care of me even though you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had to. You were also just a kid back then. I love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="today-at-school"&gt;Today At School
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m back at school after a 4 day weekend from thanksgiving, and today I have Developing Scalable Weeb Applications, where we learn how to connect our code projects to a database and use SQL in our code to help us build and modify the data in our database. I also have Calculus, Intro to English Comp, and Web-Based Software Projects, which ends at 8pm each night. Most of these classes I like, especially the last class. It&amp;rsquo;s a project class where we work on teams of three to create a web-based application using a database. My team is currently working to create a webapp similar to the OG twitter, but for shower thoughts! No pictures, no videos, no threads&amp;hellip; Only posts, reactions, and maybe replies! I am very excited for the end product, and I will make sure to post screenshots when it&amp;rsquo;s done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also a member of my schools Unified Student Government (yippee!!!) as a Senator. Today we discussed student initiatives, and thanks to my suggestion we are soon getting a brand new refridgerator dedicated for the students! WOO! Finally we won&amp;rsquo;t have to compete with the school clubs and activites for fridge space. We also discussed ways to encourage third-year students to actually show up to their internships (because TWO companies backed out of working with our school due to so many students not showing up). So far our ideas are to create large posters to put at least a couple on each floor (it&amp;rsquo;s a very small school), and have a QR code for students to see &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the internships are about about, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they work, and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they are so important (our careers quite literally rely on it). But we&amp;rsquo;ll see how well that goes over, or whether these lazy bunch of students will ruin a good thing &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; for the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="world-news"&gt;World News
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="ad-fatigue"&gt;Ad Fatigue
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video on Tiktok about ad fatigue, oh my GOODNESS I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; damn tired of ALL the ads!!! &lt;strong&gt;Everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;!!! Instagram and Pinterest are especially egregious, Pinterest you can&amp;rsquo;t even tell what&amp;rsquo;s an ad and what&amp;rsquo;s a post, and every time you try to scroll you end up triggering a random ad to go to its link. On Instagram, almost every other post is some sort of ad, and &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; every 2 reels videos is one or two ads. Luckily, tiktok ads are (for now) relatively easy to get rid of, and my husband and I pay for Youtube Premium so no ads there (and he found an extension that blocks promotions inside each video on our TVs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, why the hell am I getting marketing emails for companies I&amp;rsquo;ve either never heard of or don&amp;rsquo;t have an account with?? It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that hitting &amp;ldquo;unubscribe&amp;rdquo; from the majority of these emails doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Oh yeah, this also happens because your email gets sold. So that&amp;rsquo;s freaking &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Black Friday also isn&amp;rsquo;t the same thing it was when I was a child, not even a full 20 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole month long debacle where sales only go up to a regular 40% when it used to go up to 80% or 90%. Companies (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Target, Michaels, and Amazon) are even faking sales, where they hike up the price and make the sale price match the &lt;em&gt;original damn price!!!&lt;/em&gt; People are already boycotting these companies (as they damn well should) and soon it&amp;rsquo;s going to bite the rich in the ass (Target and Starbucks are already feeling the pain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The lines between being a human being and being a brand are so blurred that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to distinguish between the two.&amp;rdquo; Hannah Glenn&amp;rsquo;s (@hannahglennhannahglenn on tiktok) recent video is why I decided to write on this topic. She talks about how nothing in life feels like an authentic experience anymore, and I wholeheartedly agree. From making friends and going out to hang, to watching your favorite creator on your platform of choice. Every time someone creates a good new thing, they end up getting a hard on for the concept of capitalism and making even a tiiiiiny bit more money through ad revenue. You can&amp;rsquo;t even go on a nice walk anymore without seeing at a minimum of one influencer &lt;em&gt;per walk outside&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d be surprised if smaller countries didn&amp;rsquo;t start banning the act of influencing because of the sheer amount of assholery that these weirdos perform just to get a few extra clicks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen way too many videos of influencers getting dragged online for abusing waitstaff or killing homeless people in the name of a &amp;ldquo;joke&amp;rdquo; (fuck you, Nat Reynolds, you don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to forget even though you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;only human&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho. I gotta get started on my project class&amp;rsquo; work. TTFN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you know me personally and read this far, let me know if there&amp;rsquo;s anything you want me to talk about from my perspective! ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Cover Image Owned by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.freepik.com%2Ffree-photos-vectors%2Fabstract-gradient-background&amp;ved=0CBoQjhxqGAoTCKi3trzxmJEDFQAAAAAdAAAAABDHAg&amp;opi=89978449"&gt;FreePik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>