<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beginner on Mel's Blog</title><link>https://melblogs.online/tags/beginner/</link><description>Recent content in Beginner on Mel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melblogs.online/tags/beginner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://melblogs.online/p/first-post/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First Post" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving 2025. It is 1:41pm and 55°F, which is wonderfully chilly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house with my husband and another friend, to spend Thanksgiving dinner with this friend and his family. &lt;br&gt;
I want to take a second to give space to all of the Native American tribes that were abused, murdered, kidnapped, and ultimately changed by settlers who took everything from Native people. You all deserve peace, to have your land back, and to have your languages back and your pre-colonial history not forgotten or erased. &lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t really celebrate Thanksgiving, because of its history. My only &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; is the excuse to see friends (like this friend) who I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get to see outside of special occasions and holidays, due to both parties being too busy on a normal basis. &lt;br&gt;
It feels like with adulthood comes the lack of care for holidays. I tried to hold onto it, the childhood magic that your family desperately holds onto for you and your cousins. However, growing up came with living across the country from the rest of your family, which then comes with never seeing your relatives (and never messaging or trying to see each other because neither of you seem to care at all), and over the years you end up feeling estranged from everyone. Thankfully I still keep up with one cousin and my younger brother, and they both keep up with me (and I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; thankful for them!) &lt;br&gt;
Anyways, this blog is going to be my way of processing life. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go to therapy yet, as my school schedule is so busy, but I know I still need to be responsible to myself and take care of my mental health. So, I will be talking about college and things I learn and struggle with, exciting things that happen (like how I was elected to the Unified Student Government), vacations, things with friends, drama, and personal things like how I saw a nutritionist and was told I was in &amp;ldquo;mild starvation&amp;rdquo; and how horrified I was. If you took the time to read all of this, thank you, and I hope you stick around for my other posts &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>